I'm doing well.
我都挺好的
There's no need for concern,
你也不用担心
okay?
好不
Well,
行啦
I should hang up.
挂了吧
Goodbye.
拜拜
Let's wrap up the call.
挂吧
You're working overtime, aren't you?
你不是还加班呢吗
Bye.
拜拜
Did you update Meng'an
又跟你们家领导
on the progress of your work again?
汇报工作呢
I am still worried.
这 放心不下嘛
By the way, I need to talk to you.
我正好想跟你商量个事
What's up?
什么事啊
Ask for leave.
请假
You asked it before. It's approved.
你不请过了呀 可以啊
I mean,
是这样的
currently,
现在
the project is
我们整个工程进度啊
really picking up speed,
都已经赶了一赶
and everything is going smoothly.
一切都挺顺利的
I am thinking of
我是想着
taking time off
这以后每个周末
to go back home
能不能
every weekend.
我都能回去看看
Is that too much?
过 过分哈
But
但
I have no choice.
但真的是没办法
Meng'an is about to
就是现在 梦安
go into labor.
这 快到预产期了
The baby is full-term
孩子也足月
and could arrive at any moment.
随时都有可能生产
I want to be there for them
我就想多 多陪陪她们
as much as possible
心里面也
to feel more secure,
比较能够踏实嘛
you know?
对吧
Lin,
师哥
are you secretly
你是不是背着我
working on something big
在春江
in Chunjiang behind my back?
搞什么大项目了呀
Nonsense.
瞎说
Am I such a person?
我是 我是这种人吗
I mean it.
真的我
I just want...
我就是
Want...
就是想
Is it okay?
可以吗
I'm serious.
真的 真
Meng'an is so lucky.
梦安命真好
Lin,
师哥
why can't I
你说我怎么
be as lucky as she is?
没有那么好运呢
No,
不
you're not like us.
你跟我们不一样
You're all about achieving big things
你是搞大事情的人
and fully committing to science.
献身科学嘛
After you.
李主任 请
Let's do big things together.
一起搞科学
Xin, look.
心心 看
Little Watermelon is awake,
小西瓜醒喽
raising her little feet.
宝宝翘着小脚丫
Is she cute?
小西瓜漂亮吗
Are you missing your mom, huh?
想妈妈了 是不是啊
Good girl.
好乖哟
Love you.
爱你呦
Love you, little feet.
爱你呦 小脚丫
Look at her little feet.
你看 小脚丫
Hello, ma'am.
您好 女士
Your skin looks great.
我看您的皮肤底子不错
Want to give
要试用一下
our cosmetics a try?
我们的彩妆吗
No, I'm good.
不用了
Are you hiring for a salesgirl?
你们是在招聘柜姐吗
Ms He.
何经理
I'll go over there first.
那我先过去啦
Are you applying for our open positions?
你要应聘吗
You have a
看您这个形象
great image.
还挺不错的哈
Your makeup
今天妆面
is very well done.
化得也挺精致的
It seems like you
看来您应该对
have a good understanding of
化妆跟彩妆
makeup and cosmetics, is that right?
有一定的了解吧
The thing is that
是这样
we're looking for a staff who can
我们呢 是希望找一个
do live commerce.
能直播卖货的
Do you have any
不知道您之前
relevant experience in that field?
有这方面的经验吗
I'd like to try it.
我想试试
Hey girls, check out
姐妹们 我们先看
this 10-color eyeshadow palette.
这一款十色眼影盘
It feels really weighty in your hand.
拿在手上重量感十足
There are ten different color options.
有十个颜色可以选择
Personally,
那我个人呢
I've tried out every color.
每一个颜色我都用过
It's super practical
因为它非常地实用
because you have soft,
那它有柔光
shimmery, and pearlescent
偏光和珠光
options.
可以选择
This color is great
一般我们上班
for work
通勤的话呢
or when you're on the go.
用这个会比较保守一点
Also, let me show you this.
但即便如此
It's sturdy
压得好实啊
and has a lot of powder.
量好足
You can notice its impact in my hand.
你可以看一下我上手的
The hue is quite subtle
很浅 很淡
and natural.
很自然
Haowen.
浩文
Haowen, Haowen.
浩文 浩文
Xin.
老婆
Did you check the video I sent to you?
看到我给你发的了吗
Why are you doing live commerce?
你怎么去卖货去了
Didn't you want to be an art teacher?
你不要当美术老师吗
It is a waste of my pretty face
你媳妇我长这么漂亮
to be an art teacher.
当美术老师可惜了了
Listen,
我跟你说
I've figured out
我想明白
what we're going to do.
我们要干什么了
What?
干什么呀
Live selling.
直播卖货
I don't know how to do that.
这我可不会
Our company did this before,
之前咱们公司搞这个
and we've screwed it up.
不就搞砸了吗
You screwed up the company
就是因为你不会
because you didn't know how to do it.
才把公司搞砸了
Remember how we started our company?
你想啊 咱们开公司
We began making imitative goods
从最早的
in the garment market
在服装市场做打版货
and then ventured into our design and
到后来
branding business to open an online store.
自己做设计品牌开网店
We've always been ahead of the game,
每一步都走在别人前面
except when
唯独在
we switched to live commerce.
往直播带货转型的时候
That's when we fell behind.
掉队了
It's my fault.
那这都怪我
I was too focused on
我之前光想做
opening off-line stores
做线下实体店呢
and missed the live commerce trend.
错过这浪潮了哈
But we can make it right.
落下的功课就得补
We're getting into live commerce now.
我们现在就开始做直播
I'll do live commerce during work hours.
平时呢 我在门店播
I'll continue it after off work.
回来我也接着播
Once I figure out how
咱把这个直播的逻辑
live commerce works,
给搞明白了
I'm confident that
再加上你
with your experience in apparel,
这么多年的服装经验
we can definitely make a comeback.
一定可以东山再起的
Then
回头
we can clear away
回头把这个 这个
this, this,
还有这个 这个 这个
and this.
全都收一收
I will do live commerce here.
就在这儿播
The big day is finally here.
这一天终于要来了
Yeah.
对啊
Tomorrow is the high school entrance test.
明天就中考了
Are you feeling a mix of
有没有点小激动
excitement and nerves?
小 小紧张
I'm feeling okay.
还好吧
I won't be able to go back tomorrow.
爸爸明天回不来啊
You won't blame me, will you?
你不怪爸爸吧
No, I don't.
别
You must not
千万别
come back specifically
别因为我这个考试
for my test.
专门回来啊
It will only add pressure on me.
别给我压力
I won't.
我 我不给你压力啊
Even if I want to, my boss won't
你看我领导也
approve my leave,
不给我假呀
right?
是吧
Then I'm feeling secure.
那我就放心了
You both
你们也是啊
must not give me pressure.
都别给我压力
Let me sit the test
让我静悄悄地
peacefully and
保持平常心
surprise you with my scores.
然后惊艳你们所有人
Really?
真的假的呀
Are you bluffing?
这个牛吹得有点大
Surprise us with your scores, huh?
惊艳我们所有人
You don't know who my mom is?
你也不看看我是谁女儿
I'm born smart.
随谁啊
That's true.
也是啊
Take it easy.
放轻松
You can handle the test.
小小的一个中考嘛
Come on.
加油
Yunjie,
云阶呀
look what I made for
快看大姑给你准备的
you!
啥
Are you on a video call?
又视频呢
Li Lin,
李临
don't stress Yunjie out too much.
别老给孩子压力
Let her chill.
让她放轻松点
Listen,
我跟你说
don't feel anxious.
别有压力
No big deal.
没啥
Even if you don't perform well,
考不上
you can follow my steps of
咱就上护校
attending a nursing school and carrying
跟着大姑干
on our family tradition of practicing TCM.
继承咱们家的中医祖业
Don't worry, aunt.
不用了 大姑
I will take the test seriously.
我一定会好好考的
Come on,
来
having a Must-Win Cake
吃个定胜糕
ensures you an excellent score.
中考成绩好
Aunt, is it reliable?
大姑 你这靠谱吗
For sure.
当然靠谱了
In ancient times,
早年
the famous general Yue Fei
岳飞打仗以前
ate this before going into battle.
都吃这个
Want some?
你吃不吃
If not, I'll take it away.
不吃我拿走了
Yeah,
吃吃吃
there's no harm in believing.
梦想还是要有的
What if it comes true?
万一实现了呢
Right.
对呀
If you can dream it,
不怕做不到
you can do it.
就怕想不到
Look,
快看
here's a gift for you.
妈妈的礼物
It's like a dress
你这是啥呀
for the Spring Festival Gala.
穿得跟要上春晚似的
Dad, look at it.
爸 你看啊
Xin said that this dress
是你小姨说
will give you a great score,
说穿这个 能旗开得胜
so I bought it.
我就给买了
Okay.
穿
I must wear it.
必须穿
Alright, I will keep it for you.
那我先给你收着
Dad,
爸
Mom and Aunt
妈和大姑
both prepared gifts for me.
都给我准备礼物了
Where's your gift?
你的呢
That reminds me.
对啊
What should I do?
怎么办 我
I think I forget it.
爸爸好像忘了
You can't be here,
你人不到
now even the gift, either?
礼物也不到吗
Who's there?
谁呀
Wait a moment.
来啦
Hello,
您好
are you Li Yunjie.
请问是李云阶吗
Yes.
是
Your flowers.
您的花
Thank you.
谢谢
Goodbye.
拜拜
Is this the gift you got for me?
是你给我买的礼物吗
Yes, secret gift for you.
神秘小礼物
Wish you stand first tomorrow.
祝你明天啊 一举夺魁
Come on.
加油 加油
I know
我知道
each gift you give me
你们的套路
contains your good wishes.
不都是谐音梗吗
Thanks, Mom.
谢谢妈
Thanks, aunt.
谢谢大姑
Thanks, Dad.
谢谢爸
I really appreciate it.
你们的心意我全部接收
Let me hug you.
抱抱 抱抱
Come on, Yunjie.
加油啊 闺女
Mom,
妈
can I sleep with you?
我能跟你一起睡吗
Sure, come here.
来 快上来
Okay.
好
What's wrong?
怎么啦
Are you nervous about
是不是因为明天要中考
tomorrow's test?
有点紧张了
It's okay.
没事的
Mom,
妈
how long before you
你还有多久
have your baby?
就要生宝宝了
About
大概
four weeks.
四周左右吧
My test results
那到时候我的中考成绩
should be released by then.
应该也差不多出来了
Are you afraid?
害怕呀
Mom,
妈
they say that
有人说
taking this exam is like
中考就是
thousands of troops crossing
千军万马过独木桥
a narrow bridge. If you fall off
要是一不小心
the bridge,
从桥上掉下来
your life is basically over.
人生算是没戏了
Who said that?
这谁说的呀
Life is never that simple.
人生哪儿那么简单呀
A single test can't determine it.
一次就定成败了
What about
那你说那些
those successful folks
没读过书
who didn't even
没上过大学的
attend school or college?
成功人士
What are their opinions?
他们怎么说呀
Don't worry. There's always a way out.
没事的 总会有办法的
Mom,
妈
He Lu told me you'll
何璐跟我说
have your second baby in a few weeks.
再过几周你就生二宝了
After that, you won't
到时候 就不是
only be my mom.
我一个人的妈妈了
Then, the baby
那他（她）
will be
也会是
your only sibling.
你一个人的兄弟姐妹呀
Yunjie,
云阶啊
thanks to your presence,
爸爸 妈妈
Mom and Dad have experienced great joy
当年因为生了你
over the last decade.
这十几年过得很幸福
Therefore, we are confident that
所以我们也相信
the arrival of Little Grape
小葡萄的到来
will double the happiness
会让我们全家的幸福
of our family.
翻倍的
In the future,
将来
you and Little Grape will grow up.
你们肯定都会长大
Me and your dad will grow old.
爸爸妈妈也会变老
Then you and Little Grape
你们就会是世界上
will be the closest ones in the world,
最亲的亲人了
just like Jing and your Dad,
就像 大姑跟爸爸
Me and Xin.
妈妈跟小姨一样
You two will never be apart
是一辈子
in your lifetime.
都不会分开的亲人
Isn't that good?
这不好吗
Yes.
好
Give me a hug.
来给妈妈抱抱
You will be
我们云阶长大了
a good sister.
会是个好姐姐的
Xin, is this place all for live commerce?
心啊 这全都是直播的
It is the biggest hub
这儿是全国最大的
for live commerce.
直播基地
To start from scratch,
我们既然要从头开始干
we must delve into
那就要学习呀
live commerce.
研究直播这个行业
Am I correct?
你说对吧
Honey, you're amazing.
老婆 你真厉害
Is that a live commerce building?
那大楼都是直播间
This one.
就是这个
Let's go.
进去吧
Okay.
走
He is the famous...
这是那
who's his name?
这是那个谁呀
You're the...
您是
the...
那叫什么
I can't remember it...
什么
Sorry.
对不起
Forget about it.
想不起来就别想了
I just remembered.
我想起来了
I still can't remember.
我还是没想起来 快走
We exclusively occupy
这一层
the live studios on this floor.
都是我们的直播间
Our company has signed dozens of
我们公司 签了几十个
e-commerce anchors
不同成长阶段的
at various growth stages.
带货主播
This face mask
这款面膜呢
hydrates the skin well.
它不仅有补水的效果
Can I enter the room?
我能进去吗
It also helps firm skin
对这个皮肤的提拉
and reduce
祛皱
wrinkles.
有特别好的功效
This couple is
这一对
among the most popular anchors
是最近我们直播间里
of our live studios.
数据特别好的一对夫妻
At first,
其实一开始
we didn't take notice of them.
我们也没有重视他们
However, their
但就是这种
homely style
亲切感的风格
has a solid appeal to the audience.
特别有说服力
Customers appreciate this approach.
消费者就是喜欢
No need to strain your eyes.
不用看得这么费劲
Go inside to see closely.
进去看
Really?
可以进去啊
Be quite.
别出声
This deal is too good to pass up.
抓紧机会 不要错过
Seriously,
大家可以看到
this product
这个真的是
is a real bang for your buck.
物超所值的啊
Yeah, it works like a charm.
对 这个效果特别好
It won't make you look pale.
不会那么地显白
Come on, I'll remove
来 我给大家
the makeup to show you.
卸了看一下啊
No need, honey.
别卸了 媳妇
See,
你看
the online audience
直播间在线观看人数
is zero.
零
The platform will soon
那平台推流
provide us with data traffic.
都是一波一波的嘛
We need to stick to it.
我们要扛住
Look at your sad expression.
你看你这臊眉耷眼的
Let me help you.
我来 我来 我来
Don't bother.
没事 没事 我来
I can do it.
没事 没事 没事
Anyway, there is no online audience.
反正现在直播间为零
No one will notice it.
大家也看不见
It takes time for the platform
这平台推流
to provide us with data traffic.
都是一波一波的
We have to tide over
我们就要扛住
the period where
这直播间人数
there's no audience.
为零的时候
Then, the platform will
这平台才可以
provide us with data traffic.
给我们推流量啊
I think the platform
我觉得平台
is ignoring us.
都不看咱们一眼
They are scamming us.
肯定就是骗我们的
How could it be?
怎么会呢
Don't we both agree to
我们俩不是说好了吗
stick it out
要坚持
until we make it?
才能被别人看见
Your mouth is so dry.
嘴巴都这样了
Don't push yourself too hard.
还坚持呢
I'll use some glycerin at night.
我晚上涂点甘油就好了
Look at these famous e-commerce anchors.
你说那些个博主
None of them got successful overnight.
人家哪有一下成名的
They've really been through a lot.
那不都是苦过来的吗
Right? True.
也是 对吧
No pain, no gain.
谁不吃点苦啊
Honey, you're the best. You'll become
我老婆是最棒的
the most popular e-commerce anchor.
你会成最牛的博主
I know you have my back.
有我老公在后面支持我
Let's steer clear of promoting lipsticks.
咱们先不播口红了
How about promoting face masks instead?
换一个面膜播 好不好
Okay.
好
Check out this face mask. It is
这一款面膜
a moisturizing mask made by Mizhiyan.
宓之妍莹润保湿面膜
Lately, it's been scorching out.
现在的天气呢 比较热
Honey, check it out.
媳妇 快快快
Online audiences
上人了
are entering.
直播间来人了
Dear, check them out.
宝宝们 看一下
Those moisturizing masks
这款宓之妍
made by Mizhiyan
莹润保湿面膜
are sourced from
我呢
the shopping mall
拿到的是商场的货源
and are guaranteed authentic.
保证是正品
Meng'an,
梦安
which one do you want?
吃哪个
Cherry tomatoes.
西红柿吧
Okay.
好
Which one?
吃哪个
It's enough, Jing.
够了 姐
Take the tomatoes first.
你先吃 我给你备着
Okay.
好
What if we have to wait for a long time?
万一咱等时间长呢
It's sweet.
甜的
You can have more.
你多吃
These facial masks
这款面膜呢
are not sourced from the shop mall.
不是商场渠道
This anchor is good.
这家还行啊
It is a pretty good deal.
你看优惠力度还挺大
Jing, look at that.
姐 你看那个
Is that woman watching Mengxin?
女的手机里是梦心吗
I guarantee this is the best price
保证全网最低价
you'll find. If you want
喜欢的宝宝们
this, purchase from the link No.1.
可以拍下一号链接
Excuse me,
姑娘
ma'am.
我问一下
Which platform
你现在看的
are you watching?
这是哪个平台啊
It is Taomao.
这个呀 淘猫
The anchor is my relative.
这个女的是我们家亲戚
Oh, really?
你们家亲戚啊
By the way,
那你们家亲戚
she looks fine.
还挺好看的
You're so kind.
真会说话
Honestly,
我跟你说啊
she looks better in real life.
她本人更漂亮
She's not photogenic.
不太上镜
Really?
是吗
I found it.
找着了 找着了
It's indeed Mengxin.
真的是梦心
Here comes the link No.1 for masks.
面膜一号链接
Okay.
好
Next is the link No.2.
接下来我们上二号链接
When does she start doing this?
她什么时候开始直播了
The link No.2 Is for
二号链接是我们这一款
this celebrity lipstick. We keep
明星口红
restocking this one for our audiences.
是我们屡屡返场的这个
You look great.
可以啊
This dress suits you well.
这个小裙子穿挺好啊
How's it going?
怎么样
Are you glad wearing the old clothes?
旧衣服穿着心里还美吗
Not really.
确实没有那么美啊
It must be hard for you in these years.
那些年委屈你了啊
It's supposed to be Mom to comfort you.
这话应该咱妈说吧
No.
不
only you
你说
can bring me comfort.
我心里才舒坦
Here's a lipstick for you.
送你个口红
Look,
看
it's natural.
纯天然的
and safe for pregnant women.
孕妇也能用的
The color looks nice, huh?
怎么样 颜色还不错吧
Where is it from?
哪儿来的
The brand sends it
品牌方送的
to me for the live streaming.
让我直播用
Did you quit the art teacher job?
美术机构又不干啦
Yes.
不干了
Your marriage with Haowen
你除了对老贾这件事情
is stable.
能有点长性以外
Why can't you be stable
做其他的事
in your career?
能不能也再多点长性啊
Why do you start nagging once you see me?
你怎么一见面就要说我
You're my sister.
你是我妹妹
Why can't I nag you?
还说不得了
Okay.
行行行
You're under the control of hormones.
你现在孕激素高
I won't take your words to heart.
我不跟你一般见识
Let's talk seriously.
好好说
The boss of the art education school
美术机构那老板
is a scum.
是个人渣
Did he bully you?
他欺负你了
He didn't dare to do it.
他倒是想 他敢吗
I threw a cup of sour liquid
我泼了那个色鬼
all over him.
一身酸水
Did you disfigure him?
你把人毁容啦
Just some lemon water.
柠檬酸水
You're
你这
able to defend yourself now.
不算是窝里横了哈
Yeah, I am making progress.
人嘛 总是要长大的
Why do you suddenly
那怎么突然
want to do live commerce?
又想到直播了呢
Why not try other jobs?
干点别的不行吗
At first, I just wanted to try.
刚开始只是试一试
After discussing with Haowen,
但是我跟老贾商量好了
we both think live commerce is good.
我觉得直播挺好的
Think about it.
你看啊
At first, Haowen and I
当初我和老贾呢
were unfamiliar with
就是因为对直播带货
live commerce.
不熟悉
That's why we fell behind
才在电商这个环节
in the e-commerce.
掉了队
We're now trying to
我们现在
re-familiarize ourselves with this field.
想重新熟悉这个领域
Haowen and I will definitely
今后我和老贾
make it in the future.
一定会东山再起的
What do you think about it?
你觉得怎么样
It is not impossible.
也不是不行
Live commerce
直播
itself is
本身就是
an enhanced e-commerce platform
电商平台的一个进阶版
that has become a part of
现在又是大家的
everyone's daily life.
一种生活方式
In the long term, it shows potential.
长远看肯定是没问题
However, live commerce is not easy.
但是做直播 很辛苦的
It entails speaking extensively every day
每天要讲很多话
and testing numerous products.
还要试很多品
Your lips are peeling, possibly because
你看你的嘴 都起皮了
you've been trying lots of lipsticks.
试口红试的吧
And those are just the tip of the iceberg.
这还只是表面看到的
There are many aspects related to
那后边还有好多门道呢
live commerce, such as sourcing channels,
渠道啊
product selection,
还有选品啊
after-sales, handling returns,
然后售后啊 退货呀
and the risks
搞不好还有
of criticism from your followers.
粉丝会在网上骂你
Have you taken them into account?
这些你都想好了吗
No.
没想好
I don't want to consider them.
我也不打算去想
I only know l cannot
可是这个家
let Haowen shoulder
不能再
the family burden alone.
只靠老贾一个人了
I have to help him.
我也得顶上来啊
The challenges you mentioned
那你刚才说的那些
are indeed
难不难
complex.
那都难
But every industry is challenging.
你想做哪行不难啊
Doing good in one industry is harder.
要想做得好 就更难了
However, Haowen and I have
可是我和老贾
overcome difficulties
就是这么
to reach where we are today.
一路难过来的呀
When we face challenges,
有什么事
we discuss them
我跟他一块儿
together,
有商有量的
just like
就像当初
when we started from scratch.
我们俩一块儿创业一样
If we could stick together
那当初我们能一起
through the bad times
过苦日子
at the beginning,
能一起难过来
why can't we do it now?
现在为什么就不行了呢
Well.
你看
Also,
再说了
I love
干这个
live commerce,
也是我自己喜欢的
right?
是吧
I can wear makeup
那个 打扮呀 化妆啊
and try nice clothing
穿漂亮衣服呀
without spending a penny.
还不用花自己钱
Is that cool?
多好
Okay.
行吧
Since you have decided,
既然你们都想好了
I won't interfere with you.
就干吧
Can you help me?
那你帮帮我
How?
我怎么帮你啊
You can do marketing
你营销啊
and planning.
策划呀
I can't do it.
干不了
Why?
怎么干不了
You just
你刚才
talked a lot about it.
说了那么一大堆呢
My salary is high.
我很贵的
Let's not talk about money.
谈钱多伤感情
Even with brothers, keep clear accounts.
亲兄弟明算账啊
We are sisters.
咱俩是亲姐妹
That's the same.
那不一样吗
Give me my clothes.
脱下来
I will never give you my clothes.
以后旧衣服也不给你穿
I don't want them.
我还不稀罕呢
You've been through a lot.
我妹妹可怜了
I'm doing well.
不可怜
My hormones are at the upper hand.
孕激素有点高
Take them down.
降下来 降下来
Relax.
稳住
Dear,
各位宝宝们
check out the number one product today.
我们今天的一号产品
It is a
是这一款
super hydrating face mask.
深层补水面膜
The mask
它这个面膜呢
is made of plant fiber,
是植物纤维膜
which sticks to
它能够更好地 紧密地
the skin better.
贴合于肌肤
Let's see what's
家人们 我们看一下
inside the mask package.
这一款面膜里面哈
Dad,
爸 来了
here you are.
爸
There are five serum bottles
里面呢 是五瓶精华素
and five sheets.
还有五片精华膜
Each serum bottle
那一瓶精华素呢
has 1.5 ml of
里面有一点五毫升
hydrating essence
满满的补水精华
packed with hydrating ingredients.
里面富含多种补水成分
When using the mask,
我们用的时候呢
apply the serum first.
先敷这个精华素
Dear,
好了 宝宝们
you're all like family to me.
你们是我的家人
But
但是许阿姨
my parents
自己的爸爸妈妈
are coming to visit,
也来到了直播间的现场
so I need to take time off
所以我先去
to spend with them.
陪他们一会儿
I'll return in 15 minutes
等十五分钟之后
to continue
我再来继续
hanging out with you all.
我们的宠粉时刻
I will go gently,
轻轻地我先走了
just as I will
正如我一会儿
come back gently later.
还会轻轻地回来的
See you.
拜拜
Well done.
真好
Hurry, I'm sweating.
快 热坏了 热坏了
Take a seat.
快坐
Have some food.
快吃饭 吃饭
Dad.
爸 爸 爸
Xin,
心心
have more cucumber to cool down.
你多吃点黄瓜 去火
It's delicious.
好吃 好吃
I'm eating.
我吃着呢
The braised pork made by Dad
爸做的这个红烧肉
tastes really good.
真好吃
Xin always enjoys Dad's cooking.
心就爱吃 爸做的饭
How about the soup I made?
那我做的汤呢
It's so tasty that
好喝极了
I can't stop myself from having more.
我喝得肚子都胀了
Remember to
那个
drink that beverage tea.
一会儿多喝点那个
Sure.
好嘞 好嘞 好
It contains boat-fruited sterculia seed.
胖大海 那个润嗓子
Time's almost up.
差不多了 接着播了
Wait, what's that?
不 怎么了
Let me see it.
我看 我看
It's okay.
没事
Let me take a look.
我看
Your lips are chapping.
这嘴皮都破了
Mom,
是 妈
I'll take care of Xin.
我照顾她 我照顾她
I'll put on some glycerin before bed.
我晚上涂点甘油就好了
Does it hurt?
多疼啊
Mom, it is the golden time
妈 黄金时间
to reach more online audiences
要接住一批流量
and gain more followers.
还能涨一批粉呢
Yes.
对 对 对
You should go home to take rest.
你们赶紧回去休息
Xin,
丫头
can I give you some advice?
我给你提个建议呗
I see you're selling lipsticks
你现在不是卖口红
and facial masks now,
和这个面膜吗
aren't you?
对不对
Can everyone,
面膜是不是
regardless of age or gender,
男的女的 老的少的
use the masks?
是不是 都能扣上
Yes.
是
You're right.
是是是
Later, you can say,
你一会儿说
dear,
亲们
hello,
你们好
this is my mom.
这是我的亲妈
She's over 60 years old.
年芳六十有余
My mom didn't look like this
我亲妈以前这张脸
previously.
不是这样
After using this facial mask...
自从用了这个脸膜以后
Then, you show your mom to the audience,
完了 往那儿一拽
saying, take a look.
你看看我妈妈
Doesn't she look in her 40s
哪像六十有余
instead of over 60?
像四十有余
Good.
行
The audience will then rush to
然后那些亲们
make a purchase. Does that sound good?
都下单 多好啊
Yeah,
我跟你说
I've seen this strategy
我在直播间看的
used in
人家那个真 真是
other live commerce streams.
把那妈拉进来
Give me a break.
行啦
Mom, Mom.
妈妈妈
You can apply the filter to my face.
美颜 一美颜就年轻啦
I can try the lipsticks.
口红我可以来做呀
Time's running out.
快到时间了 下场
I can assist you with the lipsticks.
不是 口红我也可以啊
Look at me.
你看
I'll consider it,
那个 我 我考虑一下
alright?
好吧
You can brainstorm some aliases first.
你们起个名字
For example, my name is Auntie Xu.
我叫许阿姨 你叫什么
Once you come up with a name,
你想好了 回头
you can do the live commerce.
回头你来播
Next time, we will host a live commerce
下一场咱们弄一专场
event featuring both of you.
我专门给你
Auntie Xiaoli.
小丽阿姨
Xin's Auntie Xu.
那个你都阿姨了
We can not be the same generation.
我不能跟她平辈啊
I can't...
我不
Well, how about
我得 婆婆
Granny Xu?
许婆婆
I disagree.
什么婆婆呀
Make it young.
往小里说
Little Sister Li'ning.
丽宁小妹妹
hurry up and go home.
你快回去吧
Little Sister.
小妹妹 小妹妹
It's time to go home.
赶紧回去
Remember to turn on the AC.
吹着空调比什么都好
Then we are leaving.
那我们走了
Okay.
好好好
Bring the umbrella.
来 伞呢 伞呢
See you.
走吧 走吧
Don't worry.
不用 不用 不用
Then go home early.
那你早点回去啊
I'll be back soon.
马上就回去了
Don't worry.
一会儿
Don't be too tired.
别太累了
Alright.
好嘞 好嘞
Dad, take it easy.
爸 慢点
Wrap it up early.
早点回去啊
I got it.
好了 好了
Don't get sunburned.
别晒着
Go back to turn on the AC.
快快快 回去吹空调去
What idea were you thinking of?
你这都什么呀
The idea is brilliant.
我这办法多好啊
How can I be 40 years old?
还四十
Don't doubt it.
那当然了
You look exactly...
你一看就是
They care about you.
爸妈心疼你
like 40 years old.
四十多岁
You look like 41 years old.
四十有一
Let's continue.
接着播
Xin is
你说心心
working
她又要上班
and livestreaming.
又要直播
She talks non-stop every single day,
她每天都说那么多话
repeating herself
一遍一遍
over and over again.
一遍一遍地说
Her lips are chapping,
她的嘴都说破了
and her voice sounds strained.
嗓子都哑了
What kind of life
你说心心
is she living?
她过的什么日子啊
Before this...
以前
But now,
她现在
she's struggling a lot,
这么遭罪
which has never
她 从来没有
happened before.
受过这么多苦
Your lips are dry.
嘴唇干了 嘴唇干了
Take one sip.
吸一口 吸一口
I never imagined that doing live commerce
我真不知道这个直播
can be so demanding.
这么辛苦
You're right.
是是是 是
I'm really concerned about them.
我真的心疼他们
How can we
你 你说我们
help her?
怎么帮她呀
I listen to you.
你说怎么办 就怎么办
Since we're getting older,
现在老了 啥也干不了
the best thing we can do is
只能帮他们
support them in caring for
把孩子带好
the children to lessen their burden.
减轻他们的后顾之忧呗
Yeah,
对对对
you're right.
后顾之忧
If anyone
以后谁要是
dares to say that
再说我们心心
Xin is spoiled and unreasonable,
吃不了苦 矫情
I won't let them get away with it.
我就跟他没完
Sure.
拼命 拼命
It's so hard for Xin.
太不容易了
Don't cry.
你别哭了
Your tears are making me want to cry.
你哭得我都想哭了
I feel like crying.
我都想哭
Then
那
I won't cry.
不哭了 不哭了
You're making me teary-eyed.
你 你这哭得我
No, don't cry.
不是 你别哭啊
I will stop crying.
我不哭了
But you're crying so much.
不是 你
It feels like I don't
我不哭
care about Xin if I don't cry.
好像我不心疼姑娘似的
Don't cry.
别哭了
Then you stop crying,
不不不 不哭了
alright?
你不哭哈
I'm trying to
我不哭
I won't cry.
我不哭 不哭
Let's go back home.
走 回家
Let's go.
回家 回家
Go home.
回家啊
Please don't cry.
不哭了啊
You're doing great.
乖 乖 乖
Li'ning, keep it up.
丽丽啊 乖 丽丽
Look,
你看啊
that guy seems suspicious.
这男的 指定是有事
Why are you staring at me?
看着我干什么
Focus on the movie.
看电影
The movie isn't as attractive as you.
电影没你好看
But you can't just keep staring at me.
那也不能老盯着我看哪
Do I bother you?
不愿意啊
No, I'm so happy.
高兴着呢
How long has it been
咱们俩有多长时间
since last time we've
没这样
had some alone time here
单独在这里
like this?
待着了啊
Since Yunjie
打从云阶
was born,
出生以后
we've always gone to the movies as a trio.
看电影好像都是仨人了
We never missed a single animated movie.
动画片是一部都没落呀
Yunjie is so lucky.
云阶真是赚了
Do you recall the first movie
你还记不记得我们俩
we watched together?
看的第一部电影
What is it?
是啥
Jurassic Park.
侏罗纪呀
Yeah.
对
Titanic was playing, too.
那时候也有泰坦尼克的
Why did you
为什么非得
take me to see Jurassic Park?
请我看侏罗纪呀
Jurassic Park was so thrilling.
侏罗纪刺激
I remember Mei Yiduo
我还记得看电影的时候
called you during the movie.
梅一朵给你打电话呢
Did she?
有吗
Yes.
对哦
Didn't you answer the phone
那不是你接的电话吗
later?
后来
What did Mei Yiduo
那梅一朵跟你说什么了
say to you on the phone?
电话里
I answered the phone.
我接电话
What else could she have said?
她还能说什么呀
What do you want her to say?
你想她说什么呀
I...
我
I overthink things too much.
我想那么多干什么
Will Mei Yiduo
一会儿梅一朵
call you later?
不会给你打电话吧
No chance.
不可能
I've switched off my phone.
我关机了
You're making me feel paranoid.
你这很容易让我多想啊
It's not you who's paranoid.
不是你多想
It's your hormones
是你的孕激素
at play.
它想多了
My heart is racing fast.
这心跳有点快啊
It'll slow down if you stop staring at me.
你不看我就好了
Let me look at you
我看会儿你吧
for a moment.
看看你
Don't look at me.
别看我
Watch the movie.
看电影
The female character is not beautiful.
这女的不好看
I prefer to watch you.
还是看你吧
Okay.
行吧
Are you going to leave soon?
一会儿就走吗
I just took one day off.
就请了一天的假
When are you coming back?
那你还什么时候回来啊
Next week. I'll be back.
下个星期呗 我再回来
I'll talk to Mei Yiduo
我跟梅一朵说一声
to see if she...
看看如果手里现在
Where's the milk tea shop?
哪有奶茶店呀
Why does this girl
你说这个小女孩
look like Yunjie?
怎么长得那么像云阶呢
Hello, Mr and Mrs Li.
叔叔阿姨好
Are you two hanging out as well?
你们也出来玩呀
You're right.
你说得没错
Adults are liars.
大人都是骗子
How's the popcorn?
爆米花好吃吗
How's the movie?
电影好看吗
What a coincidence.
真是缘分哪
Yunjie,
云阶
what's up?
你干吗呢
You seem upset.
气呼呼的
Say something.
说话啊
Aunt,
大姑
Mom and Dad were too much.
我爸和我妈太过分了
They went to
他俩
the movies,
看电影
had a date,
约会
and enjoyed popcorn without me.
还吃爆米花呢
Your Dad?
你爸
Yes.
对
Yeah, he's back.
他回来啦
They were munching on popcorn.
他俩还吃爆米花呢
It's junk food.
这可是垃圾食品
Where is he?
人呢
He's back to Beijing.
回北京了
He's so busy?
这么忙呀
He passed by our home
过家门而不入
and did not even come back?
他大禹治水啊
He's always busy
科 科学家嘛
helping the country develop.
为祖国做贡献 很忙的
He got a round-trip ticket for one day.
当天往返的
How did he find time to watch movies
这么忙还能看电影
and hang out?
逛街
Snatch a little leisure from a busy life.
忙里偷个闲嘛
Liars!
叛徒
Say, how many times did he come back?
说 回来几次了
Does he come back often?
他经常回来
No, he doesn't.
没有
Just this time.
就这一回
And Yunjie ran into us.
还被她给碰见了
Movie theaters can be very noisy.
电影院很吵的
Did it affect the baby?
不会影响到宝宝吧
We were watching an art film.
文艺片
It was very dull,
特别闷
and I ended up falling asleep.
我都睡着了
Was the baby moving?
那 宝宝有胎动吗
Yes, it was.
有啊
In fact, its movements woke me up.
后来就是他给我动醒的
It was really active,
挺活跃的呢
and it's still moving.
现在还动着呢
Do you want to feel it?
你要不要试试
Touch it.
你摸摸
It's moving.
真的动了
It's so active.
好活跃呀他
It's uncomfortable at times.
有的时候还挺疼的
That's abnormal.
不对
It's moving too often.
动得太频繁了
Let's head to the hospital
马上去医院
for a fetal heart rate monitoring.
去做个胎心监测
Is mom going to give birth?
会不会要生了呀
I want to go, too.
我也要去
You're not going with us.
你别去了
Just stay at home.
在家待着
Nah, it's still a few weeks left.
不是 还有好几周呢
Maybe it's a false alarm.
应该没事吧
Listen to me.
听我的
Go to the hospital.
去医院
Does it hurt?
疼吗
Yes.
疼
You're getting regular contractions.
已经有规律开始宫缩了
Time to head into the ward for the labor.
进病房待产吧
Jing,
静姐
what's going on?
怎么样了
How's it going?
怎么样
How's An?
安安怎么样
Her cervix has expanded 4 centimeters.
医生说已经开了四指了
Where is Lin?
我 我姐夫呢
I can't reach him on the phone.
电话打不通啊
I've been calling.
我一直在打
Keep calling.
接着打 接着打
Doctor,
大夫
how's it going?
怎么样
The woman's in labor.
产妇马上生产了
Only one person can accompany her.
只能一个人陪产
I will.
我来
That's great.
真好
No matter Meng'an has a boy or a girl,
不管大姐生男孩女孩
our family will thrive.
咱家都枝繁叶茂
Health is the most important.
健康就行
You're right.
是 是 是
It's a joyful thing.
开心
What do you think?
你 你说
Is it a boy or a girl?
男孩还是女孩呢
Xin.
心
Dad, Mom.
爸 妈
Does the baby arrive?
生了 生了 生了
Yes.
生了
Come on.
快快快
Is it a boy or a girl?
男孩女孩
A boy.
男孩
One son and one daughter.
儿女双全
Let me see.
看一下
It's so joyful, Mom.
高兴 妈
Come on.
快快快
Send the baby video to Lin.
那个 发给李临
Where is he?
他人呢
He's on the plane.
在飞机上呢
Why didn't he come back earlier
我姐生孩子这么大的事
for Meng'an big day?
他为什么不早回来啊
He's back.
回来了 回来了
He got back yesterday.
昨天就回来啦
They even went to see a movie.
俩人还去看了场电影
Why did he go?
都回来了为什么要走啊
He didn't know Meng'an was giving birth.
他不知道梦安要生啊
He had work to do, so he left.
工作忙啊 他就走了
When he got the call
到了飞机场
at the airport,
接到电话以后
he hung around all night
他在机场等了一晚上
to catch an early flight back.
坐早班飞机回来
Hurry up, send it.
快快快 发
He's on the way back.
在路上了
Even though Xin sends the video,
她发了飞机屏蔽
Lin can't receive it as he's on the plane.
哪收得到啊
Once he lands,
那他下了飞机
he will be able to
是不是
see his son immediately.
第一时间
Am I right?
他就看见他儿子了
That's true.
也对
Go ahead.
发
Honey,
老婆
I'm sorry,
对不起
I...
我昨
I shouldn't
我 我昨天晚上
have left last night.
就不应该回去
I'm sorry.
对不起
Lin,
你 你 你
why do you come back?
你怎么又回来了
I can do it myself.
我自己能生
Nonsense.
这 这是
That's not the point.
你自己能生的事吗
What if Mei Yiduo...
那梅一朵
what if she
梅一朵要是
is upset with you?
生气了怎么办
You've been taking leaves quite often.
你老请假
Why do you
你这会儿
bring her up now?
你提什么梅一朵啊
I'm worried that she might fire you.
我怕她不要你了
Then, I will quit the job myself.
这班我也不上了
Is she still human
要是这会儿
if she doesn't let me
她不让我回来
come back at this moment?
那她还是个人吗
I'm sorry.
对不起呀
Well,
那我
can I just let my hormones
孕激素
take over now?
能不能 高点
Sure.
高高高
Let it be.
让它高起来
Let me
老公抱啊
give you a hug.
老公抱
You did a great job.
你辛苦了
Your mom had a boy,
你妈生了个男孩
and you got into high school.
你又考上了高中
It's a double joy for our family.
咱们家可是双喜临门啦
Yes.
是呀
I wasn't expecting
就是没想到
Little Grape to be a boy.
小葡萄是个弟弟
Silly girl,
傻孩子
a boy is great.
弟弟多好啊
Aunt,
大姑
you're valuing boys over girls.
你重男轻女
I'm putting myself
我这是站在你妈的角度
in your mom's shoes.
考虑问题
Think over it.
你看
Meng'an already has you,
你们家有个你
and now she's got a boy.
再生个小葡萄
It's like double the joy. Am I right?
这不就是一个好字吗
I know what you're thinking.
我知道你怎么想的
Little Grape,
小葡萄
I'm your sister!
我是你姐
Do you remember me?
你还记得我吗
When you were still in Mom's belly,
你在肚子里的时候呀
I told you stories daily.
我天天给你讲故事呢
My name is Li Yunjie,
我是李云阶
and you can
没事 你不用叫我全名
just call me Yunjie.
你管我叫姐就行了
From now on, you have to listen to me,
以后你得听我的话
okay?
知道吗
Yunjie, you're quite the chatterbox.
云阶 你这个话挺密啊
How about giving me a chance to chime in?
你让爸爸也说两句
Didn't you talk enough last night?
昨天晚上没聊够吗
Just leave me alone forever.
有本事一辈子别理我啊
Are you still angry?
还 还生气呢
You didn't inform her you had returned.
昨天你回来没告诉她
She's envious.
吃醋了
It's my bad last night.
昨天晚上爸爸淘气了
I just wanted to date with your mom
这不是想跟你妈妈
like we used to be.
图个新鲜吗
I missed
我这也不是
my chance,
没赶上吗
you know?
对吧
Is your son just so cute?
小孩新鲜吗
Yeah, he is.
新鲜啊
Yunjie,
云阶
did you get
录取通知书
the high school acceptance letter?
是不是拿到了
Is it a big deal for you?
重要吗
Yes, it is.
当然重要啊
No, not really.
不重要
It's not as crucial as your precious son.
没你新鲜儿子重要
What should I do,
这可怎么办呢
Son.
儿子
Your sister is starting to
你姐姐现在开始
dislike me.
不待见我了
What should I do moving forward?
以后怎么办呢
When I'm old, I have to depend on you.
等我老了还得靠你哦
You have to go shopping with Dad,
你陪着爸爸一起逛逛街
alright?
好不好
Let's listen to music and
听听音乐
go to the public bathhouse
搓搓背
to do the spa together.
逛个澡堂子
Hello?
喂
It's a boy.
男孩男孩
Yes.
对
Now you have
咱们家
a grandson.
正儿八经的大孙子
There's a male heir to our Li family.
老李家有传人了
Yes.
对对对
Yunjie.
云阶
Come on.
行了 行了啊
Hurry up and
你赶紧啊
pick a name for the baby.
给孩子起个名字
The boy's name must be meaningful.
起得有点内涵
Don't pick any random names.
别什么铁柱 钢蛋的啊
Relax.
你这
Hurry up
赶快
and get Yunjie back.
把云阶给我追回来
Yunjie,
云阶
where does she go?
去哪儿了她
Haven't you just seen it?
还去哪儿了
If you don't
你今天不把她
get her back,
给我追回来
you cannot get back to see me.
你也就别回来了
Did I make a mistake again?
我这又犯错了
Hurry up.
你赶快去啊
Okay, take it easy.
好好好 你 你慢点啊
Watch out for the baby.
你 盯着点啊
Off you go.
你快去吧你
Okay.
好好好
Stop dragging your feet.
磨磨叽叽的
Let's wrap up the call.
行 就这样
Could you lower your voice?
你能不能说话小声点
Remember, you used to be a head nurse.
你还当过护士长呢你
I was telling the good news.
我给家里人报个喜
Now, the Li Family has a grandson.
咱老李家有大孙子了
Yunjie,
云阶
wait for me.
等等我
I'm exhausted.
累死我了
Why are you walking so fast?
走那么快干啥
I'm not waiting.
不等
Your son's a real gem.
你儿子多好呀
You should go back and check on him.
回去看你儿子吧
I'm old.
你闺女都老了
No, you can't say stuff like that.
你可不能说这样话
So, if you're old,
你要是老了
what's that make me?
那你爸怎么办
How old am I supposed to be?
得老成什么样啊
You're not afraid of getting old.
你不怕老呀
Your son can serve you.
你儿子可以伺候你
He can even rub your back.
还可以给你搓背呢
I'm only counting on your brother
也就是搓背这事
to rub my back.
指望你弟弟
For other things,
其他的事
I'm still counting on you
将来啊
in the future.
还得靠你呢
Am I correct?
是吧
You can rub your mom's back
你非得动手搓背
if you want to.
你可以给你妈搓背啊
We girls don't
我们小仙女
do things like rubbing backs.
不搓背
Okay,
行行行
I got it.
小仙女不搓背
I have something serious to tell you.
跟你说个正经事
I've
爸呀
signed you up
给你报了一个
for a summer camp
游学夏令营
in Beijing.
就在北京
Do you want to go?
去不去
Didn't I promise to
之前不是答应你了吗
take you on a trip
暑假要陪你
this summer vacation?
好好地玩一下
Let's take
就这个机会
this opportunity to
爸陪你啊
climb the Great Wall,
爬长城
walk down Chang'an Avenue,
逛长安街
and visit the Forbidden City, Temple of
游故宫
Heaven, Shichahai, and the Summer Palace.
天坛 什刹海 颐和园
We can try Peking Duck,
还有烤鸭
noodles with soybean paste,
炸酱面
mutton hotpot,
涮肉
rolling soybean cake,
驴打滚
and Chinese crepes.
煎饼果子
Does it count?
煎饼果子 算吗
You can eat it anyway.
反正也能吃着
Are you finished?
说完了吗
It will be great fun.
言之不尽的好玩
I thought you
我还以为
forgot your promise.
你把我的事忘了呢
No way.
那怎么可能啊
I'll forget anything else
就谁的事忘了
but not
你的事
the promise I made to you.
不能忘
What about my mom?
那我妈呢
It's the
就 就你俩的事
same case.
不能忘
Who do you like better, me or Mom?
那我俩你更喜欢谁
Yunjie,
云阶啊
why are you making me choose between you
一定要在江边
and Mom, especially here by the river?
问这样的送命题吗
I can't answer it
回答不上来啊
I like your grandma the most.
我最喜欢你奶奶
No,
不行
you must answer my question.
我们俩你更喜欢谁
What's up?
怎么了
You've told the truth.
给你说的
I'm getting older.
我是真上岁数了
Don't call me old in the future, okay?
以后不许说我老了啊
Come on.
你看
If you didn't run, that wouldn't happen.
刚刚你要不跑就好了呀
So,
对呀 你看
I'll still need to
所以说呀
rely on you in the future,
以后还得指望你
right?
是吧